{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "dateScraped": 1585352971.7726562, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9ac41da6-7085-11ea-84d4-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9ac6117e-7085-11ea-b9fa-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9ac612a8-7085-11ea-8cf7-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "How concerned should I be about COVID\u201119 ?", "answerText": "On March 11 , 2020 , the World Health Organization ( WHO ) declared that the new coronavirus , SARS\u2011CoV\u20112 and the disease it causes , COVID\u201119 , is a global pandemic because of how fast it is spreading across the globe . A pandemic means a disease that is prevalent and spreading over the whole world . According to the WHO , this is the first pandemic caused by a coronavirus . \n   The good news for the U.S. is that if we all change our behavior starting today , we can work together to help slow the spread of the virus . Slowing the spread helps hospitals and healthcare workers keep up with the healthcare needs of the community without becoming overwhelmed .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "How concerned should I be about COVID\u201119 ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "On March 11 , 2020 , the World Health Organization ( WHO ) declared that the new coronavirus , SARS\u2011CoV\u20112 and the disease it causes , COVID\u201119 , is a global pandemic because of how fast it is spreading across the globe . A pandemic means a disease that is prevalent and spreading over the whole world . According to the WHO , this is the first pandemic caused by a coronavirus . \n  The good news for the U.S. is that if we all change our behavior starting today , we can work together to help slow the spread of the virus . Slowing the spread helps hospitals and healthcare workers keep up with the healthcare needs of the community without becoming overwhelmed .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "dateScraped": 1585352971.7855182, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9ac613f4-7085-11ea-8c1f-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9ac6146c-7085-11ea-b4cb-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9ac614c6-7085-11ea-ab87-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "How do I protect myself and others from COVID\u201119 ?", "answerText": "Coronaviruses are most commonly spread through coughing and sneezing , personal contact like shaking hands , and touching a surface with the virus and then touching your eyes , nose or mouth . \n   Slowing down the spread beginning today will help protect you and everyone else . The virus is especially hard on our most vulnerable populations , such as seniors and those with chronic medical conditions . \n   These are simple steps everyone can take to help prevent spreading COVID\u201119 and other viruses . Make them a habit now and teach these habits to those around you . \n   Wash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds , especially after going to the bathroom . Also wash them before eating and after blowing your nose , coughing or sneezing . If there 's no soap and water , use an alcohol - based hand sanitizer with at least 60 % alcohol . \n   Do n't touch your eyes , nose and mouth with unwashed hands . \n   Avoid close contact with people who are sick . \n   Stay home when you are sick . \n   Cover your cough or sneeze with a tissue , then throw the tissue in the trash and wash your hands afterward . \n   Disinfect surfaces , buttons , handles , knobs and other places touched often .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "How do I protect myself and others from COVID\u201119 ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "Coronaviruses are most commonly spread through coughing and sneezing , personal contact like shaking hands , and touching a surface with the virus and then touching your eyes , nose or mouth . \n  Slowing down the spread beginning today will help protect you and everyone else . The virus is especially hard on our most vulnerable populations , such as seniors and those with chronic medical conditions . \n  These are simple steps everyone can take to help prevent spreading COVID\u201119 and other viruses . Make them a habit now and teach these habits to those around you . \n  Wash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds , especially after going to the bathroom . Also wash them before eating and after blowing your nose , coughing or sneezing . If there 's no soap and water , use an alcohol - based hand sanitizer with at least 60 % alcohol . \n  Do n't touch your eyes , nose and mouth with unwashed hands . \n  Avoid close contact with people who are sick . \n  Stay home when you are sick . \n  Cover your cough or sneeze with a tissue , then throw the tissue in the trash and wash your hands afterward . \n  Disinfect surfaces , buttons , handles , knobs and other places touched often .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "dateScraped": 1585352971.785556, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9ac6155c-7085-11ea-bfbd-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9ac615c0-7085-11ea-a817-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9ac6161a-7085-11ea-ae7f-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Is the risk for getting COVID\u201119 the same for everyone ?", "answerText": "No , but as the virus spreads , it affects multiple age groups . People in high - risk groups for getting very sick from COVID\u201119 include people 65 years and older and those with chronic medical conditions , such as heart disease , lung disease , diabetes , high blood pressure and cancer . Those who have a compromised immune system are also at higher risk than those in the general population . \n   If you are in one of the higher - risk groups mentioned above and you develop fever or symptoms , call your doctor . If you are not sick enough to be hospitalized , you can recover at home .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Is the risk for getting COVID\u201119 the same for everyone ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "No , but as the virus spreads , it affects multiple age groups . People in high - risk groups for getting very sick from COVID\u201119 include people 65 years and older and those with chronic medical conditions , such as heart disease , lung disease , diabetes , high blood pressure and cancer . Those who have a compromised immune system are also at higher risk than those in the general population . \n  If you are in one of the higher - risk groups mentioned above and you develop fever or symptoms , call your doctor . If you are not sick enough to be hospitalized , you can recover at home .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "dateScraped": 1585352971.785588, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9ac6169c-7085-11ea-b09a-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9ac616f6-7085-11ea-8658-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9ac61750-7085-11ea-ba1a-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "What is social distancing , and should I do it ?", "answerText": "Social distancing involves staying away from other people to avoid catching or spreading a virus . It 's a fancy term for avoiding crowds and minimizing physical contact . This could mean avoiding concerts or weddings , skipping the handshake , and/or staying six feet from others . Health professionals believe COVID\u201119 spreads from person to person by droplets from coughing and sneezing . The safest thing to do during an outbreak is stay home as much as possible and minimize close contact with others .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "What is social distancing , and should I do it ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "Social distancing involves staying away from other people to avoid catching or spreading a virus . It 's a fancy term for avoiding crowds and minimizing physical contact . This could mean avoiding concerts or weddings , skipping the handshake , and/or staying six feet from others . Health professionals believe COVID\u201119 spreads from person to person by droplets from coughing and sneezing . The safest thing to do during an outbreak is stay home as much as possible and minimize close contact with others .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "dateScraped": 1585352971.785619, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9ac617d2-7085-11ea-a97b-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9ac6182c-7085-11ea-ac55-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9ac61886-7085-11ea-9e95-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Should I , or my family , go to large - scale events , sporting events , conferences and concerts ? How do I make that decision ?", "answerText": "We all want to go about our daily lives as normally as possible . But organizations are canceling and rescheduling events like conferences , rodeos and festivals . If you are considering attending a large gathering , consider your personal risk of getting and spreading the virus . If you are age 65 or older , or have a chronic medical condition , you need to be very thoughtful about your risk . Then decide for yourself whether you want to attend .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Should I , or my family , go to large - scale events , sporting events , conferences and concerts ? How do I make that decision ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "We all want to go about our daily lives as normally as possible . But organizations are canceling and rescheduling events like conferences , rodeos and festivals . If you are considering attending a large gathering , consider your personal risk of getting and spreading the virus . If you are age 65 or older , or have a chronic medical condition , you need to be very thoughtful about your risk . Then decide for yourself whether you want to attend .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "dateScraped": 1585352971.785676, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9ac61a0c-7085-11ea-81f4-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9ac61a7a-7085-11ea-af4a-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9ac61aca-7085-11ea-97c3-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "How long does the COVID\u201119 virus live on surfaces ?", "answerText": "We do n't know yet . But we do know that if you clean and disinfect surfaces often , you can get rid of the virus . Think about surfaces that you and others touch often . Those may include elevator buttons , lockers , remote controls , light switches , stair rails , door knobs , drawer pulls and appliance handles . Clean them multiple times daily . \n   The Environmental Protection Agency ( EPA ) published a list of products to use against coronavirus . Refer to it to learn about cleaning products that help slow the spread of the virus . Be sure to check manufacturer 's guidelines about cleaning electronic equipment , such as cell phones , laptops , touch screens and keyboards .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "How long does the COVID\u201119 virus live on surfaces ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "We do n't know yet . But we do know that if you clean and disinfect surfaces often , you can get rid of the virus . Think about surfaces that you and others touch often . Those may include elevator buttons , lockers , remote controls , light switches , stair rails , door knobs , drawer pulls and appliance handles . Clean them multiple times daily . \n  The Environmental Protection Agency ( EPA ) published a list of products to use against coronavirus . Refer to it to learn about cleaning products that help slow the spread of the virus . Be sure to check manufacturer 's guidelines about cleaning electronic equipment , such as cell phones , laptops , touch screens and keyboards .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "dateScraped": 1585352971.7857091, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9ac61b4c-7085-11ea-b34a-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9ac61ba6-7085-11ea-99e4-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9ac61bf6-7085-11ea-89a1-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Do home remedies work against COVID\u201119 ?", "answerText": "Home remedies and therapies are not proven to help alleviate symptoms nor ensure you wo n't get it . That 's why it is important to focus on prevention : always practice good hygiene and stay away from sick people . Eating healthy , regular physical exercise , good sleep and lowering stress levels are great ways to keep your immune system healthy .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Do home remedies work against COVID\u201119 ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "Home remedies and therapies are not proven to help alleviate symptoms nor ensure you wo n't get it . That 's why it is important to focus on prevention : always practice good hygiene and stay away from sick people . Eating healthy , regular physical exercise , good sleep and lowering stress levels are great ways to keep your immune system healthy .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "dateScraped": 1585352971.785737, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9ac61c6e-7085-11ea-bdc6-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9ac61cbe-7085-11ea-a4c2-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9ac61d06-7085-11ea-901b-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "What about my pets , are they at risk for COVID\u201119 ? What about livestock ?", "answerText": "Currently there is no known risk that pets or livestock can get sick from COVID\u201119 . However , animals do spread disease so always wash your hands after being around them . If you are sick , limit contact with animals to minimize risk to them .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "What about my pets , are they at risk for COVID\u201119 ? What about livestock ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "Currently there is no known risk that pets or livestock can get sick from COVID\u201119 . However , animals do spread disease so always wash your hands after being around them . If you are sick , limit contact with animals to minimize risk to them .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "dateScraped": 1585352971.7857652, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9ac61e26-7085-11ea-8465-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9ac62042-7085-11ea-ac65-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9ac6209c-7085-11ea-a0b2-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "Stores are running out of supplies \u2014 what do I really need and for how long ?", "answerText": "While we want to be prepared , we do n't want to strain our suppliers and hoard things our neighbors need . Protecting them protects you . Make sure you have several weeks ' worth of medications and supplies like frozen foods and canned goods for people and animals in your care in case you need to stay home .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "Stores are running out of supplies \u2014 what do I really need and for how long ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "While we want to be prepared , we do n't want to strain our suppliers and hoard things our neighbors need . Protecting them protects you . Make sure you have several weeks ' worth of medications and supplies like frozen foods and canned goods for people and animals in your care in case you need to stay home .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "dateScraped": 1585352971.785882, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9ac62218-7085-11ea-89b5-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9ac623ba-7085-11ea-bd98-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9ac6241e-7085-11ea-aaae-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "I feel sick . Do I need to get tested if I think I have COVID\u201119 ?", "answerText": "Your doctor will help make the decision whether you need to get tested , based on your symptoms and risk category . Symptoms of COVID\u201119 may show up 2\u201314 days after exposure and may include fever , cough and shortness of breath . If you are age 65 or older and/or have other medical problems like heart disease , lung disease , diabetes , high blood pressure or cancer \u2014 and have fever or symptoms \u2014 call your doctor . If you are not sick enough to be hospitalized , you can recover at home . If you are in generally good health and you get sick , stay home and take care of yourself like you would for the flu . If your symptoms worsen , call your doctor .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "I feel sick . Do I need to get tested if I think I have COVID\u201119 ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "Your doctor will help make the decision whether you need to get tested , based on your symptoms and risk category . Symptoms of COVID\u201119 may show up 2\u201314 days after exposure and may include fever , cough and shortness of breath . If you are age 65 or older and/or have other medical problems like heart disease , lung disease , diabetes , high blood pressure or cancer \u2014 and have fever or symptoms \u2014 call your doctor . If you are not sick enough to be hospitalized , you can recover at home . If you are in generally good health and you get sick , stay home and take care of yourself like you would for the flu . If your symptoms worsen , call your doctor .", "answerLinks": {}}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.dshs.state.tx.us/coronavirus/faq.aspx", "sourceName": "Texas Human Resources", "dateScraped": 1585352971.785949, "sourceDate": null, "lastUpdateTime": 1585281600.0, "needUpdate": true, "containsURLs": false, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "questionUUID": "9ac624b6-7085-11ea-adf1-8c85901aafa7", "answerUUID": "9ac6251a-7085-11ea-b12b-8c85901aafa7", "exampleUUID": "9ac62568-7085-11ea-93ef-8c85901aafa7", "questionText": "What is the treatment for COVID ?", "answerText": "There is no cure for COVID\u201119 yet . There is also no vaccine available yet , either . The best we can do is treat symptoms . Only the very sick will need hospitalization .", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "topic": "", "extraData": {"original_questionText": "What is the treatment for COVID ?", "questionLinks": {}, "original_answerText": "There is no cure for COVID\u201119 yet . There is also no vaccine available yet , either . The best we can do is treat symptoms . Only the very sick will need hospitalization .", "answerLinks": {}}}
